A Guide to the Certificates of Recognition of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1990-1993.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Certificates of Recognition of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder,
1990-1993.
The Library of Virginia
34142, 34587, 34588, 34589
Virginia. Governor (1990-1994: Wilder).
3.85 cu. ft. (11 boxes)
Administrative Information
Arranged by series.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 34142 was transferred by Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, April 22, 1992.
Accession 34587 was transferred by Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, January 14, 1994.
Accession 34588 was transferred by Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, January 14, 1994.
Accession 34589 was transferred by Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, January 14, 1994.
Historical Information
Lawrence Douglas Wilder was born in Richmond, Va., on January 17, 1931. He graduated from Virginia Union University in 1951 and afterwards was drafted into the Army, where he served in the Korean War from 1952-1953 and received a bronze star. He then attended the Howard University School of Law and graduated in 1959. Douglas Wilder was elected to the Virginia Senate in 1969 as the first African American member since Reconstruction and served in the Senate for five terms. In 1985, he was elected to the office of Lieutenant Governor as the first African American to be elected to statewide office in Virginia. L. Douglas Wilder won the election for Governor of Virginia in 1989 and served from January 13, 1990 to January 14, 1994. He was the first African American to be elected as Governor in United States.
The Office of Constituent Affairs was first established in 1984 to serve as a liaison between the Governor and the citizens of the Commonwealth. The Office oversees and coordinates responses to all mail sent to the Governor's Office. Constituent Affairs staff determine where and under whose signature the responses should be drafted and direct correspondence to the appropriate person in the administration. The Office also answers phone inquiries from constituents and occasionally meets with constituents to resolve problems and handle requests. William R. Browning served as Director of Constituent Affairs during the Wilder Administration.
Scope and Content
Certificates of Recognition, 1990-1993, are housed in 11 boxes and arranged chronologically. These records consists of copies of certificates of recognition issued by Governor Wilder to recognize citizens, programs, anniversaries, and events. Certificates of recognition are also used to designate days, weeks and months for special observance in the Commonwealth. Many certificates also include correspondence and background information, including clippings, reference material and press releases.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Certificates of Recognition, 1990-1993
Contents List
- Certificates of Recognition, 1990 (Accession 34142)., Extent: 1.4 cubic feet (4 boxes). (Box 1-4)
  Arranged chronologically by date of recognition, with separate folders each month for month designations and recognition lacking a specific date. Also includes three folders of general correspondence.
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Feb 4-10. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Feb 11-28. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Mar 1-11. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Mar 11-13. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Apr 1-15. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Apr 9-22. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Apr 22-28. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Apr 21-May 4. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 May 1-14. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 May 13-20. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 May 20-31. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 May. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 May. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990 May. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 June 3-30. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 June. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990 June. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 July 2-Aug 3. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 July. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990 July. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Aug 3-Sept 3. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 Aug. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990 Aug. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Sept 6-14. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Sept 14-23. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Sept 20-30. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Oct 1-14. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Oct 14-21. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Oct 21-Nov 4. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Nov 1-Dec 1. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1990 Dec 1-14. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition - General correspondence, 1990 Feb-May. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition - General correspondence, 1990 June-July. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition - General correspondence, 1990 Aug-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Certificates of Recognition, 1991 (Accession 34589)., Extent: 1.05 cubic feet (3 boxes). (Box 5-7)
  Arranged chronologically by date stamped on top right corner of each certificate.
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Jan 7-15. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Jan 17-22. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Jan 23-31. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Feb 1-5. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Feb 7. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Feb 12. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Feb 15-18. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Feb 20. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Feb 22-26. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition - No date stamp, 1991 Feb. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Mar 4-6. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Mar 8-13. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Mar 13-20. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Mar 27-29. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Apr 2-4. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Apr 11. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 apr 15-18. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Apr 23-25. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 May 1-2. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 May 3-6. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 May 9-10. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 May 13-31. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition - No date stamp, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 June. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 July. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Aug. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Sept 10. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition - No date stamp, 1991 Sept. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition - No date stamp, 1991 Sept. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Oct 3. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Oct 15. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Oct 16-29. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition - No date stamp, 1991 Oct. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1991 Nov 1-8. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition - No date stamp, 1991 Nov. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition - No date stamp, 1991 Dec. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Certificates of Recognition, 1992 (Accession 34587)., Extent: .7 cubic feet (2 boxes). (Box 8-9)
  Arranged chronologically by date of recognition, with separate folders for month designations and recognition lacking a specific date. Also includes five folders of 1992 certificates lacking specific month or day which are filed at the end.
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Jan. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Feb. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1992 Feb. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Mar 1-30. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1992 Mar. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1992 Mar. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Apr 3-13. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Apr 14-28. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1992 Apr. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specifc date, 1992 Apr. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 May 1-8. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 May 9-30. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1992 May. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1992 May. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 June. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1992 June. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 July. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Aug 1-27. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designation, 1992 Aug. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1992 Aug. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Sept 11-27. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1992 Sept. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1992 Sept. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Oct 1-16. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Oct 17-30. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1992 Oct. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1992 Oct. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Nov 1-28. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1992 Nov. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1992 Nov. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1992 Dec. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific month or day, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific month or day, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific month or day, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific month or day, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific month or day, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Certificates of Recognition, 1993 (Accession 34588)., Extent: .7 cubic feet (2 boxes). (Box 10-11)
  Arranged chronologically by date of recognition, with separate folders for month designations and recognition lacking a specific date.
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Jan. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Feb. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Mar 1-28. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1993 Mar. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1993. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Apr 2-18. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Apr 22-26. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1993 Apr. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1993. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 May 1-30. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1993 May. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1993 May. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 June. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 July. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Aug 2-23. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1993 Aug. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Sept. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Oct 1-16. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Oct 13-29. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of recognition - Month designations, 1993 Oct. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific date, 1993 Oct. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Nov. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Certificates of recognition, 1993 Dec. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of recognition - No specific month or day, 1993. (Box 11, Folder 8)